This sucks!
If you're gonna switch, just do it already!
What's the matter, brat?
The Innate Domain's closed off!
The special-grade is dead!
Now we just need Itadori to return safely...
Sorry, but he's not coming back.
Don't be so frightened.
I'm in a great mood right now.
Let's chat for a bit.
This is what he gets for trying to
use me without any kind of pact.
Feels like he's having some
trouble switching back.
Still, though...
It's only a matter of time.
So...
I thought about what I can do right now.
Wh-What are you...
I'm taking this brat hostage.
Hostage?!
Yeah.
I can live without this,
but that ain't true for the brat.
Switching out with me means he dies.
Also...
For good measure.
Sukuna's finger!
That special-grade cursed spirit
in there must have consumed it!
With that, I'm free as a bird.
You can be frightened now.
I'll kill you!
For no particular reason.
Our positions are reversed now.
Jujutsu Kaisen
Episode 5:  Curse Womb Must Die -II-
The only thing granted equally
to all is an unfair reality.
You just don't get it.
He's...
Itadori's coming back.
Even if that means he'll die.
That's just who he is.
You give him too much credit.
This guy's just a little tougher
and denser than other humans.
Just a moment ago, he was scared out
of his mind, on the verge of death,
and prattling on about his
regrets and all that nonsense.
I know for a fact he doesn't
have the guts to kill himself.
His arm is restored!
Healing...
He can use Reverse Cursed Techniques.
Sukuna's incarnated.
Even if he can live without a heart,
it should still be damaging to him.
I'll make him heal his heart
before Itadori returns.
I just have to make him believe he can't
beat me without a heart in his body!
Can I do that...
when I couldn't even move with
that special-grade in front of me?
It's not about whether I can.
I have to do it!
I'm finally outside, after all.
Let's use the open space.
Interesting.
You use Shikigami,
but you'll still come at me yourself?
More.
More!
Put more curse behind it
when you strike me!
Orochi!
Gang up on him!
Hey, what did I just say?
Let's use the open space!
It's not even a matter of jujutsu.
His power
and his agility
are on a different scale.
Nice technique there.
What do I do?
I used up one of my shikigami
to escape that Innate Domain.
Demon Dog White and
Orochi are both destroyed...
And Nue's at his limit, too.
I should release him
before he gets destroyed.
I get it now.
So your shikigami are created from shadows.
It makes no difference if he knows that now.
So what?
Hmm...
It's not the generic technique
that uses charms.
It's adaptable, too.
I don't get it, though.
Why did you run back then?
What a waste of talent.
Whatever.
Either way, that won't be enough to fix this.
He's figured it out, huh?
You're risking your life over stupid shit.
This brat isn't even worth that much.
Then why did you bother saving me?!
The only thing granted equally
to all is an unfair reality.
If I have the time to curse someone,
I'd rather spend it thinking
about those precious to me.
There was no room to doubt
what a good person she was.
She deserved happiness
more than anyone else.
But Tsumiki was still cursed.
The father who named me "Megumi"
with no regard for my gender
is still off living as he pleases somewhere.
Karma isn't fully automatic.
Evil people can only be judged under the law.
Jujutsu sorcerers are just another
cog in that machine of retribution.
I want more good people to
enjoy fairness, even if only a few,
so I...
save people unequally!
Nice.
That's it.
So this is when you start
burning through your life!
Now I see.
Well, in that case...
Show me, Fushiguro Megumi!
Sacred treasure swing
and ring, ring -Eight Grip-!
Just so you know, I...
don't have any logical reason
for saving you back then.
Even if it was dangerous, I couldn't bear
to see a good person like you die.
I did have my reservations,
but ultimately, it was for
selfish, emotional reasons.
That's fine, though.
I'm not a hero.
I'm a jujutsu sorcerer.
So I've never once regretted saving you.
I see.
You really are smart, Fushiguro.
You've put more thought into this than I have.
I think your conviction's a proper one,
but I don't think mine is wrong, either.
Oh, sorry, I'm almost done for.
Guess I won't have to worry about you,
Kugisaki, or Gojou-sensei.
Live a long life.
Jujutsu Kaisen
Well, tell me.
Was there any real reason
to use a precious finger
to test Sukuna's strength?
Well, there wasn't much point to it
with a half-baked test case.
But we did learn a few things.
Hmph. I'll be praying that's not just an excuse.
Stop talking! No one
understands what you're saying!
We don't understand, yet the meaning
flows right into our minds. It's creepy!
Café Restaurant
Rice
Welcome!
Would you like a seat for one?
Yes, one, please.
If you encounter it, your choices
are to either run or die.
I warned them that fighting
was absolutely not an option.
It was intentional.
Huh? What do you mean?
There was a special-grade.
Sending first-years to rescue
five who may or may not be alive
should be out of the question.
Besides, with Yuuji,
I was the one who forced the issue and
got his execution indefinitely suspended.
Some higher-ups who didn't like that
took advantage of my absence
and the special-grade
to tactfully dispose of him.
If the other two had also died,
it'd be more harassment for me
and two birds with one stone for them.
No, but...
No one expected it to become a special-grade
by the time the dispatch was issued.
Searching for someone to blame is just a pain.
Maybe I should just...
kill all of the higher-ups.
You're not usually this emotional.
It's good to see you, Ieiri-san!
Looks to me...
like you've taken quite a liking to him.
I've always been a nice guy
who cares for my students.
Don't torment Ijichi too much.
He's got it rough, stuck
between us and the higher-ups.
Keep going! Keep going! Keep going!
I don't care about a man's hardships.
That so?
So this is...
Sukuna's vessel, huh?
I can take him apart as I please, right?
Make sure to get good use out of him.
Oh, I will.
Who do you think I am?
"Live a long life"?
Doesn't mean much when
you go and die yourself.
Is this your first time having a partner die?
First time for one my age.
You seem to be taking it well, considering.
Same to you.
Of course.
I only knew him for about two weeks.
I'm not some simple woman who breaks down
bawling when a guy I barely know dies.
Jeez.
It's hot, huh?
Yeah. Wonder if it's time for summer uniforms.
What's this?
You're looking more glum than usual, Megumi.
This a wake or something?
Zenin-senpai.
Don't call me by my last name!
Maki! Maki!
I'm talking here.
Y-You actually don't know why they're so down?
What are you talking about?
Someone really did die yesterday!
One of the first-year boys!
Bonito flakes.
You should've told me sooner!
Now I look like some heartless,
cold-blooded demon!
That's exactly how you came off.
Tuna and mayo.
You're supposed to try
to make me feel better!
Who are those guys?
Our second-year upperclassmen.
You have to be kinder to your underclassmen.
There's more to kindness
than being soft on them.
Zenin-senpai is the best of all the
students at wielding cursed tools.
Salmon roe.
That's the Cursed Speech
user, Inumaki-senpai.
He can only speak in
ingredients of rice balls.
He's a bit softer when Yuuta's around, though.
Panda-senpai.
There's one more, Okkotsu-senpai,
who's the only one I can openly respect,
but he's overseas right now.
You're not adding more
about the panda named Panda?
Man, sorry about this.
And when you're in mourning...
Please forgive us for that.
The truth is, we'd like you to participate
in the Kyoto Sister School Exchange Event.
Kyoto Sister School Exchange Event?
What's that?
It's a get-together with the
other Tech school in Kyoto.
Though isn't that event
mainly second- and third-years?
And those stupid third-years
are suspended right now.
So you need to participate.
What do you do at this event?
Smash Bros.?
I won't lose if it's the Wii version.
I'll Meteor Smash so you can't come back.
Then let's make a 3-man team.
The exchange event has the principals
of the Tokyo and Kyoto schools
each propose a form of competition to be held
for an entire day over the course of two days.
Though that's just how it is on paper.
Every year, the first day is team battles,
and the second day is individual battles.
Salmon.
Individual and team battles?
We fight?! Against other jujutsu sorcerers?!
Yeah, it's a jujutsu battle
where anything but killing goes.
We'll train you up well
so you won't get killed.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Wait, do you have time for that?
I thought we were short
on jujutsu sorcerers.
That's a good question. For now, we are.
Winter Blues
Disrupt Autonomic Nerves
Change in Environment
May Blues
The glum emotions people harbor
from late winter through spring
cause an outburst of curses in the
early summer, so that's our busy season.
Sometimes we're busy all year long,
but things should be settling down soon.
Huh...
So, you'll do it, right?
You just had a partner
die on you, after all.
We're in!
I...
...have to get stronger.
I'll do anything to achieve that!
But if I decide this training and exchange
event is pointless, I'm quitting instantly.
Same here.
Well, people this cocky are
all the more worthwhile to train.
Bonito flakes.
Café Restaurant
Rice
So you're saying your boss
wants to reverse the current
positions of humans and curses.
Is that it?
Well, roughly.
It's slightly different, though.
Humans are made up of lies.
For every positive action and emotion
they show, there's always a flip-side.
Yet negative emotions like hatred and
hostility are truths without falsehood.
Since we curses are born
from those emotions,
that makes us true, pure beings!
Imitations should be eliminated!
Yet, at present, you're
the ones being eliminated.
That's why we've come to ask you.
What can we do to defeat
the jujutsu sorcerers?
If you fulfill two conditions
before going to war, then you can win.
And what are these two conditions?
The first involves the man known
as the strongest jujutsu sorcerer.
You have to render
Gojou Satoru incapable of fighting.
The second is to get Ryoumen Sukuna
and Itadori Yuuji on your side.
Hold on. He died, didn't he?
That Itadori Yuuji brat, I mean.
Did he, though? I'm not so sure.
Don't look inside me without
permission. I hate it...
Brat.
Juju Stroll
Salmon.
You stink.
I don't stink.
I don't stink!
Why are you treating me like an animal?
Because you're a panda.
Mustard leaf.
You smell like an animal.
I keep telling you to take
a bath, and you never do.
I don't like getting wet.
But unlike you guys, I don't sweat,
and I Febreze every day.
So I don't stink.
So that's what happened.
You guys try taking a whiff.
Doesn't really stink.
Sort of smells like the sun.
Sunshine!
Episode 6:
After Rain